# Nicole Dagnenica | Full Stack Web Developer

# <u>Summary</u>

Full Stack Web Developer and Digital Art Designer with a passion for learning and developing my skills in the exciting environment of web development and design. I have experience in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS and Photoshop and a background in product development. Through my career with a major retailer, I have developed strong skills in design, communication, team-building and management that will make a positive impact on a company's profitability.

# <u>Projects</u>

E-Comm: Links to: Coming Soon

An E-Commerce application where a user can create a business and sell products.

- · Created a full stack E-Commerce application using the React, Redux and Ruby on Rails framework.
- · Designed application using a mobile first approach with HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Implemented CRUD actions on database models.
- Used restful routing and dynamic routes.
- Designed database schema and wireframe.

#### Project Dashboard: Links to: Github Repo, Heroku App, Video

A project management application which a business can use to create and track client projects.

- · Created a Ruby web application using Ruby on Rails CRUD, MVC framework.
- · Implemented restful routing and nested routes.
- · Designed database schema and stored data using Sqlite and Active Record.
- · Added validations and flash error messages to prevent invalid data from being saved.
- Leveraged Bcrypt to secure user passwords and authenticate logins.
- · Used OmniAuth and Oauth authentication with Github.

# Project Dashboard with Javascript: Links to: Github repo, Heroku App, Video This is an extension of Project Dashboard project.

Created an internal API and used AJAX to render an index, show and form submission .

#### Sleepy Star: Links to: Github Repo, Heroku App, Video

A web application for a user to track a Baby's sleep schedule.

- · Created a Ruby web application using Sinatra CRUD, MVC framework.
- · Designed database schema and stored data using Sqlite and Active Record.
- · Added validations and flash error messages to prevent invalid data from being saved.
- · Leveraged Bcrypt to secure user passwords and authenticate logins.

### Book Review: Links to: Github Repo, Video

Ruby to create a CLI application to view the top 50 books that all kids should read before they are 12 years old as provided and reviewed by Common Sense Media.

- · Used Nokogiri to scrape data from Common Sense Media.
- · Created objects using Ruby.

# **Employment**

#### Macy's Merchandising Group, New York, NY (2004-2012)

Associate Project Manager, Ready-To-Wear Moderate & Alfani (2011-2012)

· Supported the GVP in managing product development and buying calendars for major private brands.

#### Associate Product Manager, Ready-To-Wear Sweaters & Woven's (2006-2011)

- Developed new product from original design concept to in-store delivery.
- 2010 Product development responsibility for \$43M landed cost shipments.
- Brand Recognition Award 2009: recognized for exceeding margin results and sales plan by 7% with a 23% increase over prior year.
- · Liaison among design, color, technical and overseas offices.

#### Associate Acount Manager, New Business Development (2004-2006)

- Account Manager of Private Label brands with Hudson Bay Company, generating sales volume of 16.7M with an increase of 20%.
- Top Performer Award 2005: Award for exceeding shipment plan by 56%.

## **Contact**

nnardella@gmail.com New York, NY (201) 874-6680 Portfolio Site Github Blog Linkedin

## **Skills**

Ruby
Ruby on Rails
SQL
Sinatra
Javascript
React
Redux
HTML / CSS
Responsive Design
Git / Github
Secure Password Authentication
Wireframing
Photoshop

# **Education**

#### Flatiron School (2018- 2019):

Online Software Engineering Program for developing web applications.

#### S.U.N.Y Empire State College

(2018): Digital Art & Design: Photoshop - GPA 4.0

#### Codecademy (2018):

Pro Intensive: Build Websites from Scratch: Certificate

# Johnson & Wales University, Providence. RI

- Bachelor of Science, Marketing, 2001
- Associates of Science, Computer Business Applications, 1999
- · Dean Lists Honors